♪ ♪
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Previously on Star Trek:
Strange New Worlds...
UHURA: Spock. meet James Kirk.
first officer of the Farragut.
UNA: When I took my commission.
I spent a week shadowing Pike.
It made all the difference.
PELIA: You want to
know the worst thing
about living almost forever?
The loss of those you love.
UNA: It wasn't
your fault. Chris.
PIKE: I led the mission.
We're responsible for
other people's lives.
The lives of my crew
mean everything to me.
KIRK: Our job puts
us up against death
more than is fair.
Now. you can let death win
or you can fight back.
KIRK: First officer's
personal log. Stardate...
What is the star date?
They're all blending together.
Farragut is conducting
a planetary survey
of Helicon Gamma. an
uninhabited M-class world
outside Federation space. and...
...I am so deeply bored.
I find myself
constantly questioning
Captain V'Rel's orders.
It's like she's
allergic to risk.
We're out here to
get our hands dirty.
to be explorers.
not to triple-check
every sensor reading.
I get it.
She wants to do
everything by the book.
Any changes since last night?
I just think the book
would be more interesting
if I got to write it.
V'REL: Helm.
bring us into a low
geosynchronous orbit
over the northern continent.
Captain V'Rel. if I may.
we could get much
more detailed readings
from an even lower orbit.
-How low do you suggest?
-Lowest orbit there is.
Our boots on the ground.
Given the geological
instability.
it seems an unwarranted risk.
Risk is why we're
here. isn't it?
Starfleet could
have sent a probe.
but instead they sent us
because some things you
need to see for yourself
-to truly understand.
-Captain.
an unknown force just impacted
-Helicon Gamma's surface.
-Report.
ALVAREZ: There's a seismic
disturbance in the planet's crust.
(explosion)
-Red alert.
-(alarm sounding)
Helm. take evasive action.
All hands. brace for...
(electrical crackling)
(coughing)
(indistinct
announcement over P.A.)
(heavy impact)
(alarms sounding)
KIRK: Medical team
to the bridge.
This is the USS Farragut.
We need immediate assistance.
We've taken heavy...
Sir. something's interfering
with the comms signal.
I'm trying to
identify the source.
It's coming from that.
PIKE: Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages of
the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
...to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
...to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
♪
♪ ♪
SPOCK: Readings?
Life signs on board.
but barely enough
to crew the ship.
Multiple systems
non functioning.
-What in Baird's name happened here?
-Whose name?
The Scottish inventor.
Everyone knows John Logie Baird.
(man coughing)
-Rescue?
-That is our purpose.
The question is:
rescue from what?
I only saw a
glimpse. It was huge.
-He's got internal bleeding.
-(pained groan)
I need to get him to sickbay.
I'd better go to Engineering
and check there's
still a warp core.
Report back with your findings.
We will offer our assistance
to Captain V'Rel on the bridge.
-(comms chime)
-Wait.
It's not just ship to ship.
All comms are down.
We'll have no way to get
in touch with each other.
Go. But find your
way to the bridge
as soon as you can.
(whirs slowly)
Don't you shut down on me.
CHAPEL: Reinforcements
have arrived.
(pained groan)
Where's your CMO. Ensign?
Just you. then.
(groaning)
I'm seeing a lot of
blunt-force injuries in here.
-What happened?
-ENSIGN: You should ask the captain.
Bed four.
Captain V'Rel. I'm Nurse Chapel.
You have a cerebral contusion.
There's no cranial swelling.
I need to get back
to the bridge.
Mm-hmm. right after we make sure
that your brain
isn't herniating.
-Stay.
-(groans)
Our away team is
heading to the bridge.
They can help.
Try bypassing primary sensors.
See if anything's functioning
in the lateral array.
(heavy impact)
Alvarez. get us
out of this debris.
Sir. it's too dangerous
without the sensors.
-Captain...
-Captain V'Rel left me the conn.
and it's up to me
to return it intact.
Mr. Spock.
Ensign Uhura. La'An.
-Welcome aboard.
-LA'AN: James.
Quite a mess you've
gotten yourself into.
Seems to be my specialty.
It's a miracle you
got our distress call.
-Signal was jammed.
-UHURA: The interference has
wreaked havoc with us. too.
But I might be able to
set up line of sight.
-Permission to borrow your telemetry?
-More than granted.
Alvarez. aim us
at the Enterprise.
Stand by for the captain.
Captain Pike.
I'll dispense with
the pleasantries
since we're still in
a critical situation.
Is the threat still in the area?
Unknown.
Tell me what you do know.
We were in the middle
of a geological survey
of Helicon Gamma when...
well. there's no
scientific way to put it...
all hell broke loose.
-Planetary instability?
-No.
A focused gravitational
beam aimed at the planet.
Aimed by what?
A ship capable of generating
a tractor beam that
powerful would have to be...
Several orders of
magnitude bigger
than any starship on record.
I know. It sounds
crazy. but it's true.
We barely saw it. It
wasn't interested in us.
We were just collateral damage.
(quietly): Destroyer of Worlds.
PIKE: And it just disappeared?
When the debris hit.
we lost sensors.
comms. all critical systems.
Captain V'Rel was
injured but lucid enough
to give the evacuation order.
Escape pods have been deployed.
I'm keeping a
skeleton crew aboard
so Farragut doesn't
become a salvage job.
Well. you've
performed commendably.
but let's get you all to safety.
Number One. I want
all Farragut crew
-beamed aboard immediately.
-UNA: Aye. Captain.
Full evacuation. We'll
start with the escape pods.
-PIKE: Proceed.
-Captain Pike...
I know. I wouldn't want
to give up my ship either.
but the safety of the
crew has to come first.
It's the right call.
We have some critically
injured patients in sickbay
-and no doctor.
-Ensign Uhura.
confirm with Chapel
which patients require
immediate evac and get
them to Enterprise.
-On it. Captain.
-Before you evacuate.
transfer all tactical
info on this mystery ship.
I want to be ready if
they take another swing.
I have restored some
function to sensors.
Sending what little
data we have back
with Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
Beaming back now. Captain.
I'll hand this to
you personally.
Energize.
-Now put all your systems...
-(transmission breaks up)
KIRK: Uhura. get him back.
What happened?
-I don't think I can.
-Why not?
Alvarez. I need you on tactical.
-Prepare all weapons.
-Aye. Commander.
SPOCK: We have visual on
Enterprise. They are engaging.
Whatever we've got.
fire at that thing.
That is illogical.
Enterprise's weapons
were clearly ineffective.
Our targeting systems are down.
Firing would serve
little purpose
-and risk damaging Enterprise.
-Well. we have to do something.
We can't just sit here.
SPOCK: At present.
I am afraid that
is all we can do.
Diagnostic. I want a complete
ship diagnostic right now.
UHURA: Uh. well.
here's some good news.
-We're not being jammed anymore.
-Great.
Bridge to sickbay.
I need to speak
to Captain V'Rel ASAP.
CHAPEL: Nurse Chapel reporting.
She required an
emergency craniectomy.
which I'm not
qualified to perform.
so I beamed her
to the Enterprise
two minutes ago.
Commander. you are now
captain of the Farragut.
We await your orders. sir.
UNA: Anything you recognize?
PIKE: Klingon
maybe. Hard to say.
There's not much
left to recognize.
Some of them seem ancient.
Damage report.
Main power's off-line. all
network systems are down.
Engines. weapons.
internal comms.
Hand communicators
still are not working.
Too much interference.
-Life support?
-Working but minimal.
Send a runner.
Tell the crew to gather
in central spaces.
Areas near the outer hull are
gonna get pretty damn cold.
Captain. the last runner we sent
to Engineering hasn't come back.
Then we have to assume
that we've been boarded.
Did the Farragut's sensor
logs tell us anything
about the species
that built this thing?
Their hull is nearly
impenetrable to our sensors.
but it's clear they're
incredibly advanced.
Sir. have you heard
of Asaasllich.
Destroyer of Worlds?
It-it also translates
as Astrovore.
Astrovore? No.
Well. every child growing up
on a remote colony world has.
Different names. same story.
Scavenger ship.
hundreds of years old.
prowling just beyond the
edges of known space.
Consuming resources from planets
and any ship unlucky
enough to cross its path.
ORTEGAS: I heard a version when
I was posted near the border.
Klingons called it
Chach-Ka. "The Annihilator."
MITCHELL: Admiral Sawyer
told a story like that
in his Stellar
Cartography class.
The monster past
the edge of the map.
LA'AN: Whether or not this is that
ship. we know it's a scavenger.
We have to assume
that their intention
is to tear the
Enterprise apart as well.
Number One. I need you
and Ortegas to find a way
to get engine
control back online
so that when we
get to Engineering
and we stop the power drain.
we're ready to
make a run for it.
Acting captain's log.
Feels strange to say that.
Under better circumstances.
it would be thrilling.
I've asked the Enterprise
officers to fill in
for our missing bridge crew.
But they barely know me.
and now I have to
ask them to trust me.
(sighs) If I were
in their shoes...
(door chimes)
Pause recording. Come in.
(door whooshes open)
Captain Kirk. we
compiled all of the data
from our encounter
with the alien vessel.
What do we know?
Our sensors cannot fully
penetrate its hull.
so we can ascertain
little of its composition.
capabilities or crew complement.
What about weaknesses?
UHURA: Fundamental
math? Its size.
It would be hard to
generate a stable warp field
at that scale. wouldn't it?
Well. odds are.
it's slow. but...
-But then we can catch it.
-Regulations...
Regulations would
have us tuck tail
and run back to
Federation space.
By the time we reach
a subspace relay
and get reinforcements.
Enterprise will have
been ripped to scraps.
We all have people on...
My brother is on that ship.
SPOCK: As the ranking officer.
we will follow your orders.
I merely wished to provide you
with all relevant information.
SCOTTY: Those are the signatures
from the picked-apart alien
ships we saw in Nessie's gob.
Enhance that bit. would you?
(PADD beeps)
SPOCK: One of the vessels is
a D7-class Klingon cruiser.
Could any of them have survived?
Highly unlikely.
The hull plating
would be disassembled.
venting all breathable air.
Even the Klingons couldn't
fight their way out.
These scavengers. they take
what they please from ships...
damn the crew... and pervert
the tech into their own.
We've no idea what
they're capable of.
Chapel's right.
If speed is our weapon.
then we have to press it.
What speed?
Uh. with all due
respect. Commander...
I mean. Acting Captain?
Is it just Captain? Uh...
Sir. they easily could've
destroyed the Farragut
or made off with us tucked
in their bloody huge pouch.
but they didn't.
And you have a theory as to why?
Because your ship's so banged
up it wasn't worth stealing?
Well. then I need you to perform
some miracles. Mr. Scott.
We need engines and
weapons. in that order.
-Aye.
-Patch up the wounded.
Get them back to work
as soon as you can.
We need to figure out where
that scavenger ship is headed
so we can find a way
to get there first.
That's it. Let's get going.
(door whooshes open)
(phaser charges)
Really missing the turbolift.
Only eight decks and two
access ladders left to go.
(metal screeching)
(phaser charges)
Oh! Oh. no. don't shoot.
You don't live to be 5.000 by
getting yourself shot a lot.
We're on our way to Engineering.
Bad place to be right
now unless you're fond
of choking to death on
your own gurgling blood.
Wh... From what?
The umbilical!
Come with me. Come.
It's flooded with toxic gas.
It's tunneled straight
through our hull.
It's tapped into
our power systems.
our computer network.
our fuel storage.
We've barely any
auxiliary power left.
If we don't disconnect it.
we will not have
enough to escape.
If the air is toxic.
we'll need breathers
to get close to the umbilical.
Grab them. Ensign Miller
will escort your team.
The second we disconnect
from that thing.
we need to be ready to fly.
Yes. Captain.
SCOTTY: Yeah. you heard right.
You better start doing your
job. you daft piece of...
KIRK: Mr. Scott?
Everything okay in there?
Soon will be. once I've
torn a few things out
and put them back proper.
An-And how long will that take?
To do it right? Two days.
Hmm.
Why don't you start
with doing it the way
where we won't
immediately explode.
and we'll take it from there?
(chuckles thinly)
Spock and Uhura
made a breakthrough.
Oh. aye? Oh.
The mineral that the
scavenger ship was collecting
at Helicon Gamma...
it was aldentium.
Oh. I've heard of it.
A few species use it in
their... propulsion systems.
There's another world nearby
with significant deposits...
Sullivan's Planet...
directly in their path.
Inhabited?
Over a hundred million people.
Pre-warp. so the
non-interference directive
means we can't warn them.
Not that there's anything
we could do anyway.
Listen. we need to
get there first.
Set a trap for the scavengers.
You're not asking me
to warp us past them.
with the head start they've got?
Look. I can give us warp power.
but if you think this
tub will hold together
at high speed after the
beating she just took.
your bum's out the window.
The plasma manifolds...
I understand.
No. I'm not sure you do.
You were handed a
raw deal. all right?
No one can fault you for that.
But if we push this ship
too hard and it fails.
that's our fault. not theirs.
It's a risk.
But I am betting on us.
Prepare for maximum warp.
Huh.
What's the problem?
I just bypassed
every safety feature
to make a direct connection
to the helm controls.
I should've shocked the
bejesus out of myself.
Disappointed you didn't
set your hair on fire?
If there's not enough
power to do that.
there's nowhere near
enough to steer the ship.
(metal screeching)
That's a good sound. right?
The ship is happy screaming?
-It's a reminder to work faster.
-(sighs)
Can we fire the
thrusters manually?
I mean. we can if we
want to very quickly die.
The maneuvering thrusters
use a chemical reaction.
They can be triggered by hand.
MITCHELL: But with no comms. we'd
have no way to coordinate them.
With no sensors. we'd be
flying literally blind.
Who needs sensors? We have eyes.
Add to that no shields or
navigational deflector.
If we make a mistake.
which we definitely would.
we end up a scorch
mark on the wall.
PELIA: Communication issue?
I got here just in time. then.
This may be the
first time I'm glad
to have lived through the 1980s.
(muffled breathing)
LA'AN: Captain.
(tricorder beeps)
PIKE: It is hooked directly
into our power grid.
our computer systems.
and our fuel pods.
LA'AN: We could try to
sever it with our phasers.
PIKE: That much energy would
take out half the ship.
(rumbling)
LA'AN: Cover!
(phaser charges)
(pained groan)
(air hissing)
PIKE: I don't think they can
see us through the smoke.
Let's get her out of here.
Uhura. status.
Approaching warp seven. sir.
(whirs slowly)
Well. Farragut may be
held together by duct tape
at this point. but as
long as it holds...
Sensors indicate we have
overtaken the scavenger vessel.
Excellent work. everyone.
How long until we reach
Sullivan's Planet?
Two hours. if we can
maintain this speed.
I will be accepting
drinks in the galley
from everyone who said
that this was impossible.
After we have saved
your ship. of course.
Of course.
(sighs)
(rumbling)
Report.
Well. we've dropped out of warp.
and I've lost all engine power.
Captain. our
stratagem has put us
directly in the path of
the scavenger vessel.
I am aware. Spock.
It's the plasma manifolds...
they've blown out.
KIRK: Well. then
take whoever you need
and get down there and fix them.
They are gone! Beyond repair!
We'll need to put
into spacedock now
and replace them.
We just... we
pushed her too hard.
We're dead in the water.
SCOTTY: I told you. I
rechecked the numbers
and re-rechecked them. and
all three times confirmed
the warp engines are
now giant paperweights.
UHURA: We still have
some impulse power.
SCOTTY: Not nearly enough.
I'm afraid all we
can do is play dead
and hope the
scavenger ignores us.
There's a chance it'll just go
on its merry planet-eating way.
SPOCK: Our other option is to
abandon ship and escape by shuttle.
We could take one to the
nearest subspace relay
and hail Starfleet.
CHAPEL: By the
time we get there.
everyone on Sullivan's
Planet will be dead.
So we're agreed. both
options are terrible.
but we have to pick one.
In one hour it'll be here.
That's how long we've got to
decide which is least terrible.
That is not our
decision to make.
I pick neither option.
Okay. That is a bold and...
if you don't mind me saying...
highly unorthodox choice.
Okay.
Sir. he's just concerned.
They have our crew.
and the planet they're
headed for is inhabited.
We won't be able to
warn them without...
Thank you. Ensign Uhura.
I'm up to speed on
the particulars.
No need for further discussion.
CHAPEL: Then how will we
provide you with options?
I don't need options.
I don't need chattering voices.
What I need is to clear my head.
And I can't do it
with all this...
Well. that could
have gone better.
No. How?
This is his first time
in the chair. right?
He's had the conn before
but never like this.
He's showing classic signs
of strain under duress.
The pressure he
must be feeling...
Aye. great. First he's reckless.
now he's liable to
snap like a twig.
Let's say he does.
What then. huh?
We would take steps to...
remove him from command.
And... what would those
steps be. exactly?
As ranking medical
officer on board.
it's within my power
to evaluate him
and. if he is mentally
unfit. remove him from duty.
UHURA: Okay. before we even
think about going down this road.
we should consider
that he's still working
on his command style.
Aye. Right now his
style is lacking.
That's my point.
Maybe we can help him find it.
I've seen him in
a crisis before.
when he didn't have the
pressures of being captain.
He saw something in me that
I hadn't seen in myself.
It saved my life.
I think he just
needs to be reminded
that same thing is in him.
Well. one of us
should talk to him.
He is clearly agitated.
Perhaps someone with
a less emotional style
might be more effective.
PIKE: Maurer... come on.
Maurer. stay with us.
She can't wait. We
have to treat her now.
LA'AN: What. with those
two things roaming around?
PIKE: We have no choice.
LA'AN: They're not
taking any damage.
PIKE: In here. the Port Galley.
LA'AN: No fumes. We're safe.
She's bleeding out.
-I need a med kit.
-Wait. wait. wait. I think...
If we had comms and a
functioning transporter.
we could have saved her.
You don't know.
Those ion particles
are like bullets. They rip
through flesh and bone.
primitive but effective.
(loud banging)
And yet their suits
are highly advanced.
I have never seen a device
absorb phaser fire like that.
-It doesn't make sense.
-Maybe they're from some
dark corner of the cosmos
that'll never make sense.
We have to find a way to get
through their defenses somehow.
No one has ever seen
them. but I know
they were considered
monsters. even by the Gorn.
Set phasers to kill.
(phaser powering up)
(banging continues)
(glass rattling)
I had this imported from
an Ithenite distillery.
I'll get you another one.
(clinking)
(screeching)
PELIA: As an old friend
of mine once said.
"Let there be light."
(sighs) Come. come. come.
Her quarters are...
exactly what I expected.
Here. No. no. Okay.
There you are.
Not you. (groans)
You were once bouncy
and cheerful. but when
the novelty wore off.
you got a little creepy.
How is any of this junk
going to help us
fly out of here?
Oh. my goodness.
I piloted many a
starship with this.
Granted. they were 8-bit.
but it was a good time
on a Friday night.
Ah. found it.
Take.
(chuckles) Is this a. uh.
personal massager?
Oh. this was once a
state-of-the-art communicator.
You had to plug
it into the wall.
but if people annoyed you.
you'd put them on hold.
I think there are more.
So the signals are grounded.
transmitted cable to cable.
(grunts) Take that.
Which will insulate
them from being jammed.
We're going to have the crew
strip the ship
for copper cables.
and we're going to
wire the Enterprise.
(laughs)
Go on.
Captain V'Rel and I
had an ongoing game.
For the first
time. I think I was
on my way to beating her.
but we never had the
chance to finish.
I think this is how
we left the board.
If I may interrupt.
Oh. you already have.
Don't stop now.
You rightly dismissed two
flawed courses of action.
but time is short and
we require a new plan.
It was V'Rel's move. and
I had her in a corner.
If I could just figure out
what she would have done next.
You are acting captain.
Your crew is waiting.
To keep them waiting
longer would be...
-...not good.
-Here's the thing.
I'm frozen.
I find this surprising.
Your brother speaks often
of your aspirations for command
and of your affinity
for leadership.
Actually. he said
you are not afraid to
throw your weight around.
no matter who's in front of you.
Yeah. that sounds like Sam.
And in a way he's right.
From the moment I
joined the Academy.
I was determined to
sit in that chair
faster than anyone before me
because I thought I knew better.
I thought I was better.
Whenever orders don't
make sense to me.
which happens more
often than I'd like.
I always think that I should
be the one giving them.
Earlier. I told Captain
V'Rel to send a landing party
to Helicon Gamma.
I pushed her hard on it.
Thank God she ignored me.
otherwise we'd all be
standing on the surface
when it exploded.
Good leaders know when to listen
and when not to.
(chuckles)
Well. I failed at
that test. too.
Mr. Scott warned me
not to push the engines.
but I ordered him to anyway.
I've been flying by the seat
of my pants this whole time.
making call after call
with no clue where
they'd lead us.
hoping I'd luck
into the right one.
and all I did was put us
belly up in the path of
the ultimate destroyer.
And now you are having
a crisis of confidence.
but you still have to lead.
Believe me. I'd love to.
but there's nothing
coming to me.
(sighs)
My mom was fond
of an expression.
"The dog who caught the car."
Now that I've finally
latched onto one...
...I have no idea
what to do with it.
On Vulcan. we have a
similar expression.
"The sehlat who ate its tail."
Though I would
point out you have
a significant leg up
over a quadrupedal beast.
Your human intuition.
It has guided us this far.
We are all still here.
I recommend you
keep following it.
Okay.
If you insist.
(boatswain's whistle sounds)
Scotty. how long until that
scavenger ship gets here?
Less than 20 minutes. but
that's just an estimate.
Well. it's good enough for me.
Glad to see you back. sir.
Me. too.
Look. I know we got off
to a rough start here.
and there's nothing I can say
that can make up for that.
Rousing speeches aren't
exactly my forte.
I think you're doing
just fine. sir.
But let me be crystal
clear to each of you.
Even if my actions
indicated otherwise.
I have no intention of giving
up on rescuing the Enterprise.
not with the lives of both
of our crews on the line.
Thank you. sir. I
needed to hear that.
And I need to hear from you.
What do we know?
Besides the fact that
we're dead in space.
what do we know about
these scavengers?
Their ship has to have
some kind of weakness.
Uhura. what have you seen?
Ships. a lot of them.
from across the quadrant.
It appropriates them.
steals their functionality.
and bends that to its own needs.
SCOTTY: And its
needs are bottomless.
All it does is consume
and make itself bigger.
The bigger it gets.
the more it requires.
Then it moves on to devour
the next resource. like...
it will never stop.
you know. it'll
never have enough.
Exactly. Scotty. you just
found their weakness:
their ravenous need to consume.
Bottomless greed.
We can use that against them.
How?
That's where you come in.
I need you to fill
the plasma manifold
until it's overflowing
with aldentium.
No-no. the-the manifold's
a useless husk.
and we don't have a drop
of aldentium on board.
We just need to make
it look like we do.
CHAPEL: As aldentium decays.
it gives off lots
of anti-protons.
Well. I could flood the intermix
chamber with anti-protons
and make it look like our
engines run on aldentium.
They'll catch the scent and
gravitate towards our tailpipe.
We are going to
make the Farragut
into a banquet that's
impossible for these scavengers
to resist. and when
they come to dine.
we're going to make
them regret it.
The captain has
given his orders.
I still feel funny being called
that while V'Rel's alive.
I promise to demote you at
the earliest opportunity.
Wait. so what exactly
do we do after we get these
scavengers to try and eat us?
Here's where the plan
gets a little crazy.
(laughs): This is where
the plan gets crazy?
Glad you're sitting
down. Nurse Chapel.
You especially. Mr. Scott.
are not going to love it.
(Pike shouts)
(La'An grunting)
La'An!
-(Pike and La'An grunting)
-(screeches)
-(screeching)
-(grunts)
(Pike shouts)
(La'An groans)
(phaser whirs)
(phaser charges)
(screeching)
(screeches)
(La'An panting)
(alarm sounding)
(both grunt)
(Pike gasping)
(coughing)
You all right?
(panting): Yeah.
It... didn't shoot.
Why didn't it kill me?
(air hissing)
We may only have a minute.
How do we get this thing
the hell off my ship?
Well. if we can't disconnect
it. what if we convince them to?
-How do you mean?
-Make them want to disconnect it.
Give them a taste
of something...
highly undesirable.
I see. stir up a
little acid reflux?
-Yeah.
-What about. uh. baryon particles?
That would ruin their
fuel and their day.
One of us would have to
access the waste system
beneath the warp drive.
Waste system? All
right. you do that.
I have to isolate the fuel line.
And bring a hyper coupler.
La'An?
Be careful. that other
alien's still out there.
(phaser charges)
(dial tone)
PELIA: Ladies. I
haven't done this
since I was a
roadie for the Dead.
Your species can communicate
with dead people?
-(phone rings)
-UNA: Hello?
Ah. ah. yes. yes.
Uh. uh. Lieutenant.
it's for you.
-Hello?
-Starboard thrusters are ready.
Port thrusters standing by.
Okay. Erica. don't crash.
The scavenger vessel
has dropped out of warp.
Anti-protons... anti-protoning?
We're as juicy a target
as I can make us.
Red alert. All
stations prepare for...
...well. for that.
-Ready impulse engines.
-Standing by.
How many times has she helmed?
Twice. including now.
Full impulse. Uhura.
(thrusters howl)
-Scotty. your turn.
-If you insist.
I do. Mr. Scott.
Detach at my mark.
KIRK: Mark.
Spock?
The sehlat has eaten
its tail. Captain.
The scavenger ship
has been disabled.
Uhura. get us line of
sight to the Enterprise
as quickly as you can.
MITCHELL: Incoming transmission.
It's the Farragut. audio only.
UHURA: Enterprise. do you read?
Took you long enough. Ensign.
Good to hear your voice. too.
We're pretty banged up. but we
disabled the scavenger ship.
SCOTTY: Tell her
it's just temporary.
How temporary?
UHURA: No idea. but
this is your chance.
For a jailbreak. (scoffs)
(sighing)
ORTEGAS: Port and
starboard thrusters.
give me ten percent.
-(rumbling)
-Whoa.
we got to kill those thrusters.
We are not off-leash.
(La'An grunts)
Captain. any luck
finding the fuel line?
I've got a pretty solid guess.
Hand me that connector?
And you might want
to take a step back.
If it explodes. it will take
out the entire engineering hull.
A big step. then?
(exhales)
(whirring)
Baryon particles are entering
the deuterium stream.
The mixture is... destabilizing.
Let's get the hell out of here
before we get sucked
out with this thing.
(rumbling)
Wait.
Emergency systems are rebooting.
ORTEGAS: Captain did it.
The umbilical's detached.
Port and starboard thrusters.
50%.
Ease off starboard
thrusters. Whoa.
N-Not that easy. Give me 30%.
50%. Now wait.
50. 80.
Cut starboard thrusters.
(metal grinding)
Hate to backseat-drive. but
you're hitting the wall.
Full port thrusters.
Thruster controls
aren't responding.
That's real bad.
Wait. I have an idea.
-I'm all ears.
-(running footfalls over phone)
Commander?
(running footfalls)
(air hissing)
Yes! Starboard thrusters to 20%.
Keep us even.
Captain.
PIKE: The scavenger.
The scavenger vessel's systems
are coming back on line.
They are targeting Enterprise.
Lock phasers.
Uh...
SPOCK: Sir. the
grapplers have proven
to be resistant to our weapons.
Okay. Spock.
What do you got?
(alarm beeping rapidly)
(laughter)
(phasers charge)
Mr. Spock. scan the
debris for life signs.
Approximately 7.000 life signs.
but they are dwindling quickly.
Can we beam survivors aboard?
(sighs)
Not even if we wanted to.
There's too much debris
to get a transporter lock.
Captain?
The life signs.
Yes. Mr. Spock?
SPOCK: The life
signs are all human.
The markings on the hull.
Can you get us a clearer image?
SCOTTY: Aye.
UHURA: I found this in
our historical database.
In the mid-21st century.
before first contact
with the Vulcans.
a group of scientists believed
that Earth's environmental
crisis was too severe
to recover from. so
they built a ship.
They hoped it would
carry humanity
to civilizations
in other worlds.
But it failed.
UHURA: The ship disappeared.
The entire crew.
their families. gone.
Never heard from again.
PELIA: I remember
when it launched.
We-we hadn't yet
invented warp drive.
We'd barely put out the fires
of the Third World War.
One of the few
nations left standing
sifted through the ashes
of their space program.
scoured the world for a crew.
You might say...
...they were the best of us.
the most optimistic.
searching for a way to carry on
the flame of life.
All those people.
7.000 souls.
The descendants of the
original inhabitants.
KIRK: So what went wrong?
How did they go from that to...
...whatever it is they became?
(door chimes)
Come in.
Ah...
Just wanted to let
you know in person.
Dr. M'Benga says that
Captain V'Rel is going
to make a complete recovery.
We'll tow Farragut
back to spacedock.
Then you only have
to hold the fort down
a little while longer.
I'm imagining the look
on Admiral April's face
when he sees us pull
in with no nacelles.
He likes Aldebaran whiskey.
Maybe have a bottle ready.
You know. it might not feel like
it. but you made the right call.
We were under attack.
You saved hundreds of lives.
both here and on Enterprise.
Number of...
estimated human casualties
on unknown vessel...
...7.000.
Well. may I?
Please.
You know. when. uh...
when I got bumped
up to first officer.
I remember
second-guessing Bob...
uh. Admiral April... a lot.
-Did he ever straighten you out?
-No.
He let me learn a
very hard lesson.
The big decisions...
they seem so simple
when someone else has to
live with the consequences.
but the choices you
make in that chair...
...they are yours to make...
...and what comes after...
...that is yours to live with.
Some decisions you will regret
for the rest of your life.
but you still have to make them.
They were human beings.
Why does that make it
feel so much worse?
All I can say is...
...having empathy for your
adversary is part of the job.
But I didn't.
I didn't think of
them as people...
at all.
Until it was too late.
Well. maybe that's the lesson.
Empathy isn't conditional.
It's either given or it isn't.
They... clearly saw us.
and either they didn't recognize
us or they didn't care.
Whatever journey
they had been through
the last 200 years.
it broke them.
When they left Earth...
...they were the best
humanity had to offer.
They weren't monsters.
Is that what we would become
in the same circumstances?
I'd like to believe we wouldn't.
-Why not?
-Because of how you're feeling right now.
Because the next time
you're in that chair.
you will remember we are
often not that different
from our enemy.
And that knowledge.
from this moment on.
will continue to guide you.
Good night. Captain Kirk.
(door whooshes open)
(door whooshes shut)
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today